A woman like Mona can drive men to extremes.
The Hi-Lo Country is a drama, romance, western film directed by Stephen Frears.
An intimate story of the enduring bond of friendship between two hard-living men, set against
a sweeping backdrop: the American West, post-World War II, in its twilight.
Pete and Big Boy are masters of the prairie, but
ultimately face trickier terrain: the human heart.
Pete Calder, played by Billy Crudup.
Big Boy Matson, played by Woody Harrelson.
Josepha O'Neil, played by Penélope Cruz.
Mona, played by Patricia Arquette.
Little Boy Matson, played by Cole Hauser.
Les Birk, played by John Diehl.
The Hi-Lo Country is a 1998 Western film directed by Stephen Frears, starring Billy Crudup, Penélope Cruz,
Woody Harrelson, Cole Hauser, Sam Elliott, Patricia Arquette, Enrique Castillo, and Katy Jurado.
It is set in post-World War II New Mexico and is
based on the Western novel by Max Evans.
The film explores themes of pearl harbor, cowboy, pickup
truck, horse riding accident, cattle ranch.
The tone is emotional.